# Nārāyan Harricharan



Name: Nārāyaṇa Dās Harricharaṇ

Date of birth: 25/08/1993

Nationality: South African

Current location: India (GMT+5:30)

Languages: English, Afrikaans and Hindi

Profile

I specialize in devops engineering, but I can work on all aspects of the stack from frontend to backend. I learn, adapt and solve problems swiftly.

I have excellent written and verbal communication skills. I enjoy working in a meticulous manner, doing thorough research and thinking critically about my solutions.

I am a digital nomad and love traveling, exploring both the inner and outer worlds. By being a mindful person I am always reflecting, learning and growing.

#### Devops experience:

- Building, monitoring and maintaining high traffic linux servers and systems
- Scaling, building, monitoring and maintaining high traffic kubernetes clusters
- Scaling, monitoring and maintaining high traffic postgresql clusters
- Web app migrations
- Building CI/CD systems
- Creating internal tooling
- Dockerizing web application and other services
- Infra as code
- Infra cost optimizations

#### Backend coding experience:

- Writing API's in Typescript
- · Writing unit tests in Typescript
- Scripting in Python, Ruby, NodeJS and Bash

Experience

## Rehive

DevOps Engineer AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

- Myself and the CTO managed kubernetes clusters on scale, getting about 1.2 million requests per day
- Improved and added extra features to our custom CI/CD tool written in python
- I wrote python scripts and tools to automate recurring devops tasks and to help manage 70+ git repos
- Troubleshooting, scaling and maintaining postgresql, kubernetes, web app and internal tooling
- Implemented Grafana & Prometheus monitoring stack
- · Planning and organizing the devops roadmap, finding weak points in the infra and prioritizing new solutions
- Cost optimizations

#### Freelancer

**DevOps Engineer** 

SEPTEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

- Migrating a LAMP Stack website from bare metal server to AWS
- SensorNetworks Assisting them in creating helm charts and a monitoring solution

# **OneConfig**

DevOps Engineer APRIL 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- I was in charge of 30+ servers.
- · Creating, maintaining and migrating servers
- Updating Letsencrypt certs
- Maintaining a Cockroachdb cluster
- Automation in Bash and Go
- Dockerizing staging the staging environment
- · Cost optimizations
- Creating KVM virtual machines

## **Kurtosys**

Platform Engineer AUGUST 2017 - MARCH 2019

- This was a hybrid role where I was both involved with ops engineerings and full stack development
- I developed and architected a wordpress hosting platform in react, typescript, nodejs and bash
  - I worked mostly on the backend development (API's and scripts) and infra
  - Optimizing and improving docker images
  - o Automated DNS, TLS, CI/CD with git
  - o Implementation of the docker swarm and glusterfs infrastructure
  - o Automated the entire site creation process, glueing all the different parts together
- Created and maintained an internal gitlab server
- Infra as code with puppet and ansible and testing on vagrant

#### **Manalto**

DevOps Engineer MARCH 2017 - JULY 2017

- Creating and maintaining servers, mongodb, AWS services and CI/CD
- Dockerized the staging env in alpine linux
- Created bitbucket pipelines and jenkins for the new docker environment
- Bash scripting automated AWS route53 cname creation, init.d start scripts, docker management script, etc
- Adding AWS Cloudwatch graphs to grafana
- Setting up a private npm registry

# **OLX**

DevOps Engineer APRIL 2016 - JANUARY 2017

- I helped manage 6 OLX's websites in africa. Our biggest site olx.co.za was receiving millions of pageviews per day
- Maintaining high scale linux servers, mysql, redis
- Setup sensu for alerting
- Setting up ELK stack and creating graphs

- Automation of ssh keys with ansible
- Very basic bash and ruby scripting

#### 8Frag

**Linux Systems Administrator** 

JULY 2014 - APRIL 2016

- Creating and maintaining ubuntu and window servers
- Migrating game servers between linux and window servers
- Installation of SRCDS game servers (CS:GO and TF2), GOTV proxy servers
- Creating and modifying game server configurations
- Installation and configuration of plug-ins for the game severs
- Testing game servers and software
- Installation and configuration of unrealirc and teamspeak
- Implementation of game server web-panel TCAdmin
- Installing a monitoring solution called pulseway, later I replaced it with LibreNMS
- DDOS mitigation with bash, ufw, iptables and apache logs
- Writing tutorials on how to use and manage game servers
- · Bash scripting and SSL installation
- Client support via tickets and teamspeak
- Game tournament support and administration
- Managing and training a junior linux systems administrator

#### **Ockhams Razor**

Junior Linux Systems Administrator

FEBRUARY 2014 - APRIL 2014

- I received hands on experience with Debian Servers, RAID, BASH, AWK, SED and REGEX Scripting and also in-depth knowledge on the fundamentals of Linux LPI1.
- My training also consisted of: apt-get package management, setting up web servers with Apache, setting up e-mail servers with
   Postfix, installing web sites/panels, installing and configuring ISP config, bash scripting, mail flow troubleshooting, setting up DNS
   and configuring network interface cards.

## **Maxitec - Internet Service Provider**

**Internet and IT Support** 

JANUARY 2012 - JANUARY 2014

- Responding to all calls, e-mails, walk in clients and service call outs for diagnosing and resolving hardware, software and end users problems within agreed time scales.
- Providing efficient customer support for all issues relating to desktops, laptops, apple macs, mobile devices, peripherals, routers, WIFI, telecommunication, hosting, e-mails, VOIP and networking technologies.
- Taking ownership of a call/instruction and seeing it through to closure.
- Escalating calls and issues where necessary to seniors.
- Updating support documentation
- IT support for 'Maxiclub' Point of Sale System and helped out with Vodacom accounts and device support.

GNU/Linux - Centos & Debian	Cloud - AWS, DO, Google	
90%	70%	
Docker Swarm	Ansible	
90%	90%	
Docker	Puppet	
90%	50%	
	GNU/Linux - Centos & Debian 90%  Docker Swarm 90%  Docker	

Top Skills

Bash	Kubernetes & Helm	Virtualbox, KVM, Vagrant	
80%	60%	70%	
CI/CD	Networking	Postgresql DB Admin	
60%	50%	60%	
Monitoring & Alerting			
90%			
	Projects		
	rrojects		
github.com/Narayana108/			
github.com/warayaharoo/			
	Education		
Redhat Certified Systems Admin	istrator		
RED HAT	istiatoi	SEPTEMBER 2015	
NES IIII		SET TEMPER 2013	
	Interests		
GNU/Linux * Coding * Crypto currencies * Open-source software * Minimalism * Travel * Health * Yoga * Theosophy			
* Sanskrit			

Website by Nārāyaṇa